Guide to the Rice Unversity Center for Research in Parallel Computation (CRPC) records, Ken Kennedy, Scientific Director, 1989-1999 UA 125
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series III: Technical Reports and paper materials, 1989-1999
  - CRPC-TR93390-S: A Verified Integration of Imperative Parallel Programming Paradigms in an Object-oriented Language, Paul A. G. Sivilotti, June 1993 (Box 22, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR94391-S: A Tutorial for CC++, Paul A. G. Sivilotti, Peter A. Carlin, March 1994 (Box 22, Folder 6, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR93392: Mixed Finite Elements as Finite Differences for Elliptic Equations on Triangular Elements, T. Arbogast, C. Dawson, P. T. Keenan, 1993. Revised: June 1994 (Box 22, Folder 6, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR94393: Instructions for my C++ Elliptic PDE Solver Programs using Mixed Methods on General Geometrices, P. T. Keenan, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 7, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR94404: Application of Automatic Differentiation in CFD, A. Carle, L. L. Green, C. H. Bischof, P. A. Newman, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 7, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR94405: Performance Analysis of Data-Parallel Programs, V. S. Adve, C. Koelbel, J. M. Mellor-Crummey, May 1994 (Box 22, Folder 7, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR94406-S: A Generalized Expression Optimization Hook for C++ on High Performance Architectures, D. J. Edelsohn, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 7, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR93408: LAPACK Working Note 41: Installation Guide for LAPACK, E. Anderson, J. Dongarra, S. Ostrouchov, March 1993 (Box 22, Folder 7, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR92409: LAPACK Working Note 46: Computing the Generalized Singular Value Decomposition, Z. Bai, J. Demmel, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR93410: LAPACK Working Note 57: PUMMA: Parallel Universal Matrix Multiplication Algorithms on Distributed Memory Concurrent Computers, J. Choi, J. Dongarra, D. Walker, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 8, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR93411: LAPCAK Working Note 65: Parallel Matrix Transpose Algorithms on Distributed Memory Concurrent Computers, J. Choi, J. Dongarra, D. walker, October 1993 (Box 22, Folder 8, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR94412: LAPACK Working Note 68: A Highly Parallel Algorithm for the Reduction of a Nonsymmetric Matrix to Block Upper-Heseenberg Form, M. Berry, J. Dongarra, Y. Kim, February 1994 (Box 22, Folder 8, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR94414: LAPACK Working Note 70: On the Correctness of Parallel Bisection in Floating Point, J. Demmel, I. Dhillon, March 1994 (Box 22, Folder 8, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR92415: LAPACK Working Note 40: Block LU Factorization, J. Demmel, N. Higham, R. Schreiber, February 1992 (Box 22, Folder 8, Item 6)
  - CRPC-TR93416: LAPACK Working Note 59: Faster Numerical Algorithms via Exception Handing, J. Demmel, X. Li, August 1993 (Box 23, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR93418: LAPACK Working Note 58: The Design of Linear Algebra Libraries for High Performance Computers, J. Dongarra, D. Walker, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR92419: LAPACK Working Note 44: Performance of LAPACK: A Portable Library of Numerical Linear Algebra Routines, E. Anderson, J. Dongarra, November 1992 (Box 23, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR92420: LAPACK Working Note 54: On Swapping Diagonal Blocks in Real Schur Form, Z. Bai, J. Demmel, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR92421: LAPACK Working Note 47: Open Problems in Numerical Linear Algebra, J. Demmel, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR92422: LAPACK Working Note 53: Trading Off Parallelism and Numerical Stability, J. Demmel, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR92423: LAPACK Working Note 48: On Computing Accurate Singular Values and Eigenvalues of Matrices with Acyclic Graphs, J. Demmel, W. Gragg, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR93424: LAPACK Working Note 60: Parallel Numerical Linear Algebra, J. Demmel, M. Heath, H. van der Vorst, August 1993 (Box 23, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR93425: HeNCE: A Heterogeneous Network Computing Environment, A. Beguelin, J. Dongarra, A. Geist, R. Manchek, K. Moore, August 1993 (Box 23, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR91426: A User's Guide to PVM Parallel Virtual Machine, A. Beguelin, J. Dongarra, A. Geist, R. Manchek, V. Sunderam, July 1991 (Box 23, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR94427: Netlib Services and Resources, S. Browne, J. Dongarra, S. Green, K. Moore, T. Rowan, R. Wade, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR92428: ADIFOR Working Note 7: Extending Compile-Time Reverse Mode and Exploiting Partial Separability in ADIFOR, C.H. Bischof, M. El-Khadiri, October 1992 (Box 23, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR93429: FORTRAN M Language Definition, I. Foster, K. M. Chandy, August 1993 (Box 23, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR93430: Integrated Support for Task and Data Parallelism, K. M. Chandy, I. Foster, K. Kennedy, C. Koelbel, C. W. Tseng, August 1993 (Box 23, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR93431: Operator Overloading as an Enabling Technology for Automatic Differentiation, G. F. Corliss, A. Griewank, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR93432: A Reduced Hessian Method for Large-Scale Constrained Optimization, L. T. Biegler, J. Nocedal, C. Schmid, June 1993 (Box 23, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - CRPC-TR91433: On Designing Portable High Performance Numerical Libraries. J. Dummel, J. Dongarra, W. Kahan, July 1991 (Box 23, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR93434: Efficient Communication Operations in Reconfigurable Parallel Computers, F. Desprez, A. Ferreira, B. Tourancheau, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR93435: Successive Broadcasts on Hypercube, F. Desprez, P. Fraigniaud, B. Tourancheau, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR91436: NA-NET: Numerical Analysis Net, J. Dongarra, B. Rosener, September 1991 (Box 23, Folder 4, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR93437: A Proposal for a User-Level, Message-Passing Interface in a Distributed Memory Environment, J. J. Dongarra, R. Hempel, A. J. G. Hey, D. W. Walker, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 4, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR91438: A Parallel Algorithm for the Non-Symmetric Eigenvalue Problem, J. J. Dongarra, M. Sidani, September 1991 (Box 23, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR91439: MPI: A Message Passing Interface Standard, Message Passing Interface Forum, April 1994 (Box 23, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR93440: Trace2au: Audio Monitoring Tools for Parallel Programs, J.-Y. Peterschmitt, B. Tourancheau, August 1993 (Box 23, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR93441: Monitoring of Distributed Memory Multicomputer Programs, M. Van Riek, B. Tourancheau, X.-F. Vigouroux, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 5, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR94442: A Parallel Performance Study of Jacobi-like Eigenvalue Solution, M. Pourzandi, B. Tourancheau, March 1994 (Box 23, Folder 5, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR94443: LAPACK Working Note 69: A Serial Implementation of Cuppen's Divide and Conquer Algorithm for the Symmetric Eigenvalue Problem, J. Rutter, February 1994 (Box 23, Folder 6, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR92444: FORTRAN M as a Language for Building Earth System Models, I. Foster, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 6, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR93445: Deterministic Parallel FORTRAN, K. M. Chandy, I. Foster, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR93446: Strand and PCN: Two Generations of Compositional Programming Languages, I. Foster, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 6, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR94447: A Robust and Efficient Numerical Method for Nonlinear Protein Modeling Equations, M. Holst, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 6, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR96712: An Evaluation of Software for Computing Eigenvalues of Sparse Nonsymmetric Matrices, R. B. Lehoucq, J. A. Scott, January 1996 (Box 24, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR97713-S: A New Deflation Criterion for the QR Algorithm, Mario Ahues, Francoise Tisseur, January 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR97714-S: Scheduling Block-Cyclic Array Redistribution, Frederic Desprez, Jack Dongarra, Antoine Petitet, Cyril Randriamaro, and Yves Robert, February 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR96715: A Test Matrix Collection for Non-Hermitian Eigenvalue Problems (Release 1.0), Zhaojun Bai, David Day, James Demmel, and Jack Dongarra, October 1996 (Box 24, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR97716: A Parallel Implementation of the Nonsymmetric QR Algorithm for Distributed Memory Architectures, Greg Henry, David Watkins, and Jack Dongarra, March 1997 (Box 24, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR97717: Implementation in ScaLAPACK of Divide-and-Conquer Algorithms for Banded and Tridiagonal Linear Systems, A. Cleary and J. Dongarra, April 1997. (Box 24, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - CRPC-TR96718-S: Algorithmic Redistribution Methods for Block Cyclic Decompositions, Antoine Petitet, December 1996. (Box 24, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR96719-S: Automatic Differentiation of a Parallel Molecular Dynamics Application, P. Hovland, C. Bischof, and L. Roh, December 1996. (Box 24, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR96720-S Practical Experience in the Dangers of Heterogeneous Computing, L. S. Blackford, A. Cleary, J. Demmel, I. Dhillon, J. Dongarra, S. Hammarling, A. Petitet, H. Ren, K. Stanley, and R. C. Whaley, August 1996. (Box 24, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR96721: Key Concepts for Parallel Out-of-Core LU Factorization, Jack J. Dongarra, Sven Hammarling, and David W. Walker, March 1996. (Box 24, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR97722: High-Performance Fortran for SPMD Programming: An Applications Overview, Sanjay Ranka, Hon W. Yau, Kenneth A. Hawick, and Geoffrey C. Fox, June 1997. (Box 24, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR97723-S: Compiling Reductions in Data Parallel Programs for Distributed Memory Multiprocessors, Bo Lu, July 1997. (Box 24, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR97724-S: The Solution of a Class of Limited Diversification Portfolio Selection Problems, Gwyneth Ownes Butera, May 1997. (Box 24, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR97725-S: Compiling Stencils in High Performance Fortran, Gerald Roth, John Mellor-Crummey, Ken Kennedy, and R. Gregg Brickner, November 1997. (Box 24, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR97726: NPAC PCRC Runtime Kernel (Adlib) Definition [DRAFT], Bryan Carpenter, Guansong Zhang, and Yuhong Wen, Revised January 1998. (Box 24, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR97727: Studies of Integration and Optimization of Interpreted and Compiled Languages, Geoffrey C. Fox, Xiaoming Li, Yuhong Wen, and Guansong Zhang, February 1997. (Box 24, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR97728: A Comparison of PETSc Library and HPF Implementations of an Archetypal PDE Computation, M. Ehtesham Hayder, David E. Keyes, and Piyush Mehrotra, November 1997. (Box 24, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR97729: ARPACK++: A C++ Implementation of ARPACK Eigenvalue Package (Draft Version), Francisco M. Gomes and Danny C. Sorensen, August 1997. (Box 24, Folder 4, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR97730: On the Fundamental Role of Interior-Point Methodology in Constrained Optimization, Richard A. Tapia, April 1997. (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR96731: A Parallel Three-dimensional Electromagnetic Particle-in-Cell Code for Non-Orthogonal Meshes, S. R. Karmesin, P. C. Liewer, and J. Wang, September 1996. (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR97732-S Array Combining Scatter Functions on Coarse-Grained, Distributed-Memory Parallel Machines, Seungjo Bae, Khaled A. Alsabti, and Sanjay Ranka, March 1997. (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR97 Finite Differences vs. Automatic Differentiation for Restartable Iterative Procedures, Alan Carle and Mike Fagan, December 1997. (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR97734 Optimization Using Surrogate Objectives On a Helicopter Test Example, Andrew J. Booker, J. E. Dennis, Jr., Paul D. Frank, David B. Serafini, and Virginia Torczon, December 1997. (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR98735-S Providing Easier Access to Remote Objects in Client-Server Systems, Jonathan Aldrich, James Dooley, Scott Mandelsohn, and Adam Rifkin, January 1998. (Box 25, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - CRPC-TR97736-S A General Resource Reservation Framework for Scientific Computing, Ravi Ramamoorthi, Adam Rifkin, Boris Dimitrov, and K. Mani Chandy, December 1997. (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR98737-S Developing Peer-to-Peer Applications on the Internet: the Distributed Editor, SimulEdit, Louis Thomas, Sean Suchter, and Adam Rifkin,., January 1998. (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR98738 Construction and Evaluation of an Incremental Iterative Version of a Parallel Multigrid CFD Code via Automatic Differentiation for Shape Optimization, Alan Carle and Mike Fagan, February 1998. (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - CRPC-TR98739-S A Rigorous Framework for Optimization of Expensive Functions by Surrogates, Andrew J. Booker, J. E. Dennis, Jr., Paul D. Frank, David B. Serafini, Virginia Torczon, and Michael W. Trosset, February 1998, Revised, April 1998. (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR98740 A Ferris-Mangasarian Technique Applied to Linear Least Squares Problems, J. E. Dennis, Trond Steihaug, May 1998. (Box 25, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR97742 Real-Space Envelopes by the Connectivity Constraint: An Approach to the Ab initio Macromolecular Phase Problem, Guangzhou Zou, George N. Phillips, Jr., August 1997. (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR98742-S Bandwidth-Based Performance Tuning and Prediction, Chen Ding and Ken Kennedy, Revised, November 1999. (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR98744 On the Solution of Traveling Salesman Problems, David Applegate, Robert Bixby, William Cook, July 1998 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - CCRPC-TR98745 Loop Fusion in High Performance Fortran, Gerald Roth and Ken Kennedy, July 1998 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - CRPC-TR98746 Static Interprocedural Optimization in Java, Zoran Budimlic, Ken Kennedy,., August 1998 (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - CRPC-TR98747-S Convergence Analysis of an Inexact Truncated RQ-Iteration, Chao Yang, April 1998. (Box 25, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - CRPC-TR98748-S Accelerating the Arnoldi Iteration-Theory and Practice, Chao Yang, April 1998. (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - CRPC-TR98749 Parallelizing the Divide and Conquer Algorithm for the Symmetric Tridiagonal Eigenvalue Problem on Distributed Memory Architectures, Francoise Risseur, Jack Dongarra, February 1998. (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - CRPC-TR98750 High Performance Linear Algebra Package – LAPACK90, Jerzy Wasniewski, Jack Dongarra, March 1998. (Box 25, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - Lists of Missing Technical Reports (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - CRPC Conferences/Visits (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Online News Clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Online News Clippings, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Online News Clippings, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Newsletter Clippings (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - CRPC Directory Introduction, Calendar, Committee Lists (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - CRPC Directory Outreach, Programs, User Accounting, Affiliates (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - CRPC Directory Software, Reports, Resources, Staff, Sites (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - CRPC Directory Parallel Computing Research (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - CRPC Renewal Proposal, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - CRPC Annual Report, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - CRPC Annual Report, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - CRPC Annual Report, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Renewal Site Visit, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Annual Meeting March, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Concurrent Supercomputing Consortium 1995 Annual Report (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Linear System Solving on Vector and Shared Memory Computers (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Geophysical Parallel Computation Project (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Flow in Porous Media Parallel Computation Project, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Flow in Porous Media Parallel Computation Project, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Waterflood Simulation (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Workshop on Automatic Data Layout and Performance Prediction (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - High Performance Fortran Forum, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - High Performance Fortran Forum, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - HPCMP DoD User Group Conference, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - HPCMP DoD User Group Conference Photos (Box 29, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - 2 T-120 VHS tapes HPCMP DoD User Group Conference, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - 5 T-120 VHS tapes HPCMP DoD User Group Conference, 1998 (Box 30, Item 1)
  - 1 T-120 VHS The D Editor, Reinhard Von Hanxleden 7/6/94 (Box 30, Item 2)
  - 1 T-120 VHS Visualizations in Computational Science Summer, 1990 (Box 30, Item 3)
  - 2 T-120 VHS tapes Rn Training No. 1; Kevin Cureton: Where the ParaScope Code is Located; Available Tools; Coding Standards., 2/16/94 (Box 31, Item 1)
  - 1 T-120 VHS tape Rn Training No. 2 and 3; Reinhard Von Hanxleden: the Abstract Syntax Tree; The Symbol Table. Nathaniel McIntosh: Dependence Graphs; Symbolic Analysis. John Mellor-Crummey., 2/21-25/94 (Box 31, Item 2)
  - 2 T-120 VHS tapes Rn Training No. 5; John Mellor-Crummey: A Framework for Whole Program Analysis, 3/7/94 (Box 31, Item 3)
  - 2 T-15 VHS Portland Supercomputing, 11/15/93 (Box 31, Item 4)
  - 1 T-120 VHS Pizza Talk Elana Granston: "How (Not) To Give a Talk, 3/16/94 (Box 32, Item 1)
  - 1 T-120 VHS tape Pizza Talk Richard Von Hanxleden Value-Based Distribution in Fortran D, Summer 1994 (Box 32, Item 2)
  - 6 T-120 VHS October 1994 Conference, 10/12-14/94 (Box 32, Item 3)
  - 1 5.25" Removable Hard Disk Cartridge (Box 32, Item 4)
  - 6 T-120 VHS LACSI Symposium 2000, 8/28-29/00 (Box 33, Item 1)
  - 1 D90 Cassette Tape Fluid Modeling (Box 33, Item 2)
  - 4 D90 Cassette Tapes CRPC Annual Meeting, 10/89—Monday (Box 33, Item 3)
  - 3 D90 Cassette Tapes CRPC Annual Meeting, 10/89—Tuesday (Box 33, Item 4)
  - 2 Hard Disks "Stuff It Deluxe" (Box 33, Item 5)
  - 1 Hard Disk "Hard Disk Toolkit Personal Edition for Apple Macintosh" (Box 33, Item 6)
  - 1 Hard Disk Daymaker Organizer V. 3.0 (Box 33, Item 7)